

Goutham Devaraju

Lead iOS Developer

I'm an iOS Developer & UI/UX Designer believes in Design + Development = Perfect Engineering. Worked with startups, mid sized companies in building cool products. Heavy lifting iOS Developer, and have experience in developing more than 10+ native iOS apps. Always believes in learning new things, which always helps in making a better product.

Email:

gouthamdevaraju@gmail.com

Mobile:

+91 8801317843

SKILLS

Swift

Objective C

Continues Integration

Circle CI

Fastlane

Workflows

GitHub

Basic Shell Scripting

CoreData

GitLab

BitBucket

Analytics

Crashlytics

MVP

CocoaPods

Maps

WORK EXPERIENCE

XemplarInsights Private Limited - Lead iOS Developer

Xemplar Insights offers digital platforms and risk management solutions to Auto Insurers, and Commercial Businesses, and Families, has partnered with Cognic Systems to formally enter Indian market.

8/2019 - Present

Hyderabad, India.

- * Leading a team of 4 people.
- * Created a framework out of common module.
- Planned and implemented MVP design pattern.

Smartron India Private Limited - Senior iOS Developer

Smartron India Pvt Ltd is into the areas of smart, sensors, robotics, AI, cloud and UI/UX technologies.

8/2018 - 8/2019

Hyderabad, India.

- * Taken lead in development and deliverables.
- * Worked with a team of 8 people.
- * Collaborated in setting up Continues Integration using Fastlane and Jenkins.
- Planned and implemented MVP design pattern.
- Responsible for UserExperience, Quality and Performance.

Perk.com - iOS Developer, Research And Development

Perk is a mobile-first supply side rewards and engagement platform.

06/2015 - 08/2018

Bangalore, India.

- Worked on redesigning and architecting the applications.
- Created Static Libraries for common modules.
- *** Workflows and Continues Integration using CircleCI and Fastlane**
- Learned basic shell scripting

Paperclip Innovations - iOS Developer

Product based startup.

07/2014 - 06/2015

Bangalore, India.

- * Taken care of complete development Life cycle
- Used Scrum based methodology for the development

Stella Nova Technologies - iOS Developer

11/2013 - 06/2014

Hyderabad, India.

Worked on iPad applications which makes use of BlueTooth devices to read and process the data.

Vectorfrom Private Limited - iOS Developer

Vectorform is a platform designed to help organisations invent digital products and customer experiences.

06/2013 - 11/2013

Hyderabad, India.

* Created iPad applications for Benz, Maruthi and Lodha as proof of concept.

CERTIFICATES & ACHIEVEMENTS

HikeAthon Certificate Of Merit

Won a HikeAthon Certificate Of Merit from Hike Messenger for building a proof of concept over the night.

Google Technical User Groups (GTUG)

Won a HikeAthon Certificate Of Merit from Hike Messenger for building a proof of concept over the night.

IEEE Organisation

Active student member of IEEE Organisation. Organised and participated in many IEEE events.

Chess Champion

Won a Chess Champion ship at school.

EDUCATION

Vignana Bharathi Institute Of Technology

06/2008 - 05/2012

Hyderabad, India.

Bachelors Of Technology - Computer Science & Engineering

HOBBIES

Photo and video editing, Table Tennis, Badminton, Chess and Caroms